Guide to the Cornell University Office of Controller records, 1911-1982.
Cornell University Office of Controller records, 1911-1982
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Office of Controller records, 1911-1982.
7-1-1883
Cornell University. Office of Controller.
6.4 cubic ft.
Bonds, contracts, correspondence, blueprints, vouchers, meeting minutes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Budget figures, reports, payroll vouchers, and other records of the Controller of Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes bid bonds from various building companies for heating, ventilation, and electrical wiring, bonds to accompany proposals for building work, contract bonds, contracts for University buildings, specifications for labor and materials required for construction, articles of agreement between the University and construction companies or private individuals for construction work or materials, certification of dollars paid out or rebated by architectural firms or construction companies. Also contains a blueprint of Olin Hall, correspondence (with several letters pertaining to the building of Willard Straight Hall and signed by Dorothy Whitney Straight and the Comptroller of the University Charles D. Bostwick, 1924), meeting notes for the Cornell Plantations Committee Meeting (1947-1970), pictures (several of Clara Dickson Hall), and state leases held by the Treasurer's Office. Also budget figures, reports, payroll vouchers, and other records of the Controller of Cornell University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Office of Controller.; Cornell University--Accounting.; Cornell University--Finance.
Subjects:
Universities and colleges--Finance.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 7: restricted to permission of office of origin.
CONTAINER LIST
- Accelerator Building, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Administration Building Contracts, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4-12)
- Agricultural Advising and Research, Inc., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Agricultural Advisory Council Index, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Agricultural Experiment Station, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Agriculture, College of Albert L. Brockway, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Agriculture, Economic Building, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- Agronomy Building, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 19-22)
- Animal Husbandry Building, 1912-1914 (Box 1, Folder 23-28)
- Architectural Advisory Council, 1941-1947 (Box 1, Folder 29-31)
- Balch Hall, 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 32-35)
- Boarding Department, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Boldt Hall, 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 37-39)
- Cattle Barn, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 40-42)
- Central Ave. Bridge, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Central Heating Plant -1-, 1914-1930 (Box 1, Folder 44-49)
- Central Heating Plant -2-, 1912-1925 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Chemical Laboratory, 1915-1927 (Box 2, Folder 6-12)
- Cornell Plantations Committee Meeting, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Dairy Industry Building, 1921-1924 (Box 2, Folder 14-18)
- Dickson, Clara Hall - Contracts, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19-23)
- Diesel Engine Lab, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Diner and Garage - State St., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Drill Hall, 1914-1915; 1924 (Box 2, Folder 26-32)
- Faculty Apartments, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
- Forestry Building, 1912-1917 (Box 2, Folder 35-39)
- Golf Course, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Greenhouses -1-, 1915-1916; 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 41-47)
- Greenhouses -2-, 1915; 1926-1927,; 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
- Greenhouses -3-, 1925-1927 (Box 3, Folder 9-12)
- Home Economics Building, 1911-1915; 1931-1934,; 1939 (Box 3, Folder 13-23)
- Horse Barn (old) Durolithic Co., 1911 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Hydraulic Laboratory, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Insectary, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 26-30)
- Laundry Building, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Mennen Hall, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Newberry, J.J. Co., 1936 (Box 3, Folder 33-37)
- Nuclear Studies Laboratory, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 38-46)
- Nutrition Building, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 47-53)
- Observatory, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Olin Hall, 1941-1944 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
- Packing and Cold Storage Plant - Fred T. Ley and Co., Inc., 1922 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Piggery - G.M. Van Alstine, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Plant Industry Building, 1914-1931 (Box 4, Folder 6-11)
- Poultry Husbandry Building, 1911-1914 (Box 4, Folder 12-18)
- Residential Halls A and D, 1914-1916 (Box 4, Folder 19-21)
- Residential Halls B and C, 1915-1916 (Box 4, Folder 22-24)
- Risley Hall, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Rural Engineering, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Schoelkopf Stadium, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
- Sheep Barn - W.D. McElwee, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Sigma Phi and Psi Upsilon, 1929-1935 (Box 4, Folder 30-39)
- Steam Electric Plant, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Stock-Judging Pavillion, 1913-1917 (Box 4, Folder 41-45)
- Taylor, Myron Hall - Jackson, Robertson and Adams - Otis Elevator Co., 1927-1938 (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
- Tennis Courts, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Texas Co. State St. - Herbert H. Muzzy, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Tool Barn - R.D. Greene and Son, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Treasurer's Office - State Leases, 1921-1944 (Box 5, Folder 13-26)
- Veteran's Administration Building, 1946-1951 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Vetinary Farm - Supt. House - W.D. McElwee, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Vetinary Hospital, 1911-1938 (Box 5, Folder 29-33)
- Veterinary Hospital -1-, 1922-1936 (Box 5, Folder 34-37)
- Veterinary Hospital -2-, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
- War Memorial Group, 1927-1931 (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
- Water Supply - Whitman, Requardt, and Smith, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
- Willard Straight, 1923-1938 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Completed Projects: Weiss Reports; Ratner Committee, Report/Response (1970-1971, 1973-1974); Cost Comparison (1970-1971, 1973-1974)); Spreadsheets; Bierman; Coopers and Lybrand, Manpower Utilization Study; Dorm Authority, Prior issue; Improved Financial Management System -(Summer 1973); Ratner Committee, Supporting Data; UNR Exp - FY 1971-1974; Credit Controls; Wage/Price Guidelines; Calculation of Pay;Correspondence; Calcuation of price compliance; Second-year Price Standards: A Compendium (1980); Pay and Price Standards: A Compendium (1979); Evaluation of the Pay and Price Standards Program (1981); Task Forces - Correspondence (Box 7)
- Interinstitutional Salary Survey for the Academic Year (2 vols.), 1968-1969 (Box 8)